there are many news coming out from the
nft space lately and some if not most of
these news are not good news like for
example the news of openc a nft
marketplace being hacked and users
losing more than 3 million
so on this video i wanted to explain how
the hack happened who is responsible for
it where did the hacker put the money
but most importantly i want to make this
video to sort of warn you about any of
these the reason why is because i can
see that there are a lot of new people
that are joining the nft space and that
worries me but even though i believe
that blockchains cryptos and nfts have a
huge potential i also facepalm myself
every time that i see that somebody is
paying crazy money for a jpeg and i
double facepan myself every time i see
somebody thinking that they are an
artist because they can drag and drop a
jpeg into a website and sell it there
last weekend users from the nft
marketplace open c started to report
that their nfts were missing from their
wallets openc is an nft marketplace
which means is a website that allows
people to buy and sell jpegs of monkeys
it is not the only one but it is the
biggest one when you sell an nft in
openc you never really give openc the
nft it's not like in the real art world
where the artist paints the picture and
it gives that picture to the gallery the
gallery keeps the picture and when the
gallery makes the sale the gallery will
give that picture to the buyer openc
just provides a nice user interface they
show that you are selling your nfts but
they don't have your nfds the sale
process also doesn't happen in the openc
website when somebody wants to buy your
anything openc will invoke some code
that is stored in the ethereum
blockchain and that is the code that is
going to trigger and initiate the
transaction between you and me i will
send you some money and you will send me
your nft open c does none of that the
code is running on the ethereum
blockchain openc is just calling that
code with both of our accounts as buyer
and seller keep in mind that openc is
invoking the code but because you are
the owner of the nft when this code is
invoked you are going to have to confirm
this action that is going to happen so
if you're going to spend a million
dollars in the photo of a monkey when
openc invokes the code to make that
transfer happen you have to confirm that
transaction you have to write your
spending password to confirm the
transaction to say that that's exactly
what you want to do openc can invoke
their code as much as they want but if i
or you don't sign those invocations if
we don't sign those transactions the
code is not going to go through as we
said the code.openc is invoking lives in
something called a smart contract which
is the one in the ethereum blockchain
this smart contract is the one that has
all the instructions of what happens
after the invocation is confirmed with
our signature this smart contract is
public it's open source and it's
readable you can click and read to see
what a smart contract will do but of
course nobody reads it now if you have a
hacker mind which i'm sure you do by now
you can probably see where this is going
you can probably realize why this is a
problem openc doesn't hold anyone's nfd
the users hold their nfts and the users
are very comfortable signing
transactions that are coming from the
openc website without checking what is
the contract that they are signing the
transaction to they trust that openc is
invoking the right code they trust that
openc is invoking the right functions
and is not invoking a function that is
going to give everybody's nfts to me
because that's it they trust openc so
that's it that's what the hackers did
they didn't have to hack the open c
smart contract they didn't have to hack
the ethereum virtual machine all they
had to do was hack the users trust since
they know that the users are the ones
that have the nfts and they know that
the users really trust websites that
look like openc and they don't read the
contracts that they are signing all the
hackers had to do was send an email that
looked like it was coming directly from
openc to a link to a website that looked
like openc and it was on that website
where the users were told that they had
to do a migration of their nfts the
website invoked some code that looked
like it was going to do the migration
the users signed that transaction but in
reality the code that they signed didn't
do any of those things instead the
hackers saved the signatures of the
users and with those valid signatures
the hackers invoked their own code to
make a transaction from the wallet of
the users to the wallet of the attackers
and because the attackers had the
signatures those transactions went
through without a problem after the
attackers had the nfts they resolved
them again the money was sent to
something called tornado cash which is
what many hackers use to hide the money
tornado cash basically mixes the
transactions so they are almost
untraceable let me know if you want a
video on that now so far looking at the
attacker's wallet we can see that they
sent 1
115 earth to tornado cash and since then
they haven't moved anymore so as you can
see there was no advanced hacking going
on it was just a phishing attack
where users that trust openc too much
and they sign whatever openc tells them
to were affected they signed the wrong
transaction and they approved it without
actually knowing what was going on now
keep in mind that this is the official
story this is what openc and other
people are saying so openc is saying
that it wasn't their fault it was the
user's fault for trusting and clicking
in the wrong link but the users are
saying that they didn't click anywhere
and that this is openc's fault so as you
can see this is very recent it's a
developing story almost so we have to
wait and see what happened but the moral
of the story is that as you can see this
industry is very very very very very
very very young where maybe the
developers of openc or the programming
languages used to program these
blockchains and these smart contracts
are not really ready to actually handle
billions of dollars of value or where
maybe the people that are using these
platforms don't have the technical
background to be able to use them well
and safely and where a tiny mistake a
single click can cost millions of
dollars in losses with no one to protect
them what i think is that having no
protection for anybody in this wild west
is a double-edged sword because
cryptocurrency projects and blockchains
they are all trying to eliminate the
government from our economical systems
they are trying to create
currencies away from the central banks
and all the normal systems of power that
we know so that means that if you don't
want them you also shouldn't go for them
when you need help
and that's something that we all have to
think about are people ready to be their
own banks are you ready to keep your
savings safe this is why the
fundamentals are so important and if you
learn such fundamentals if you
understand the concepts you will also be
able to identify the scammers the
scammers the hackers the ones that
actually know what you're talking about
the ones that understand the
fundamentals and the ones that hope that
people like you and me don't know what
we're talking about so they can confuse
us and they can trick us and they can
steal our money which is exactly what
happened with openc
i made a whole series on the
fundamentals of what makes up nfts
blockchains smart contracts and all
those things so please check it out it's
all youtube and it's all for free to
watch and also remember that if you want
to become a programmer and you want to
do it for free with me then please click
the link below there you will find many
free courses that you can take on things
like javascript python react react
native nest js next js go among many
other things more than a hundred
thousand people have taken our free
javascript react react native and python
courses so click the link below but
that's just what i think let me know
what you think what is your opinion of
this blockchain crypto entities all
those things let me know please on the
comments i'm gonna be reading them right
now i think there is innovation i think
there is potential but i might be wrong
i don't claim to be an expert on these
things i'm just somebody that feels
really passionate about this but i care
about your opinion do you think it's a
scam do you think it's not going to work
do you think it's going to get better do
you think these mistakes are going to
teach us something and we're going to
build better systems or better user
experience
i hope so i don't know thank you for
watching as always stay free stay
healthy stay happy eat kimchi kamzamida
salanghayo see you on the next one bye